Clinical Research Society Records
Clinical Research Society Records
1920-1966
Clinical Research Society
1 linear foot
Mss.arc
New York Academy of Medicine Library. Rare Book Room.
Historical Note
The Clinical Research Society was founded in 1920 by a group of medical associates based in New York. Its aim was to facilitate "fellowship and mutual medical enlightenment." The Society held regular meetings featuring scientific programs and discussions on various topics, as well as annual dinners and social outings. In 1925, the Society established a scholarship loan fund for students in the medical colleges of Columbia, Cornell, and New York Universities.
Scope and Content
The collection includes general correspondence and related documents; survey responses from members; minutes and treasurer's reports; correspondence and documents related to loan scholarships; financial documents; constitution and by-laws; programs and meeting announcements; and the early history of the society. The correspondence and miscellaneous documents folder includes published articles by Society members, newspaper clippings, and obituaries.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The New York Academy of Medicine Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Clinical medicine.; Medicine -- New York (State) -- New York -- Societies, etc.; Columbia University. College of Physicians and Surgeons.; Cornell University. Medical College.; New York University. College of Medicine.; Adair, Frank Earl, 1887-; Cave, Henry Wisdom.; Doherty, William B., 1891-; Larsen, Nils Paul, 1890-1964.; Parsons, William Barclay, 1888-1973.; Stimson, Philip Moen, 1888-1971.; White, William Crawford, 1886-
Container List
  - Printed Programs. (Box 1)
  - Printed Constitution and By-laws. (Box 1)
  - Checking and Accounts Book, 1934-1952. (Box 1)
  - Receipts Notebook, 1947-1960. (Box 1)
  - Checking and Accounts Book, 1952-1964. (Box 1)
  - Inserts from Checking and Accounts Book (1952-1964), 1960-1965. (Box 1)
  - Printed Programs and Meeting Announcements. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Early History of the Clinical Research Society (typescript drafts). (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Member Data Survey Responses. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Documents, undated; 1921-1959. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Documents, 1960-1962. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Documents, 1963-1964. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Documents, 1965-1966. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1920-1935. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1936-1951. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1952-1966. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Loan Scholarship Correspondence, B-F. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Loan Scholarship Correspondence, H-W. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Loan Scholarship Correspondence, General, and signed loan contracts. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Financial Records, undated; 1926-1966. (Box 1, Folder 15)
Provenance
Donated by Dr. Philip M. Stimson.